Register of the Eric Hoffer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Eric Hoffer papers
1934-1996
94057
Hoover Institution Archives
143 manuscript boxes, 3 cubic foot boxes, 10 oversize boxes, 7 card file boxes, 1 painting (73.1 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda, printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to philosophy, social psychology, the nature of mass movements, social violence, the social role of intellectuals, and social conditions in the United States.
Hoffer, Eric.
Access
Box 142 closed until 2020 October 1. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some videorecordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to sound recordings or to view other videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1994.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection(s)
Eric Hoffer Archive, San Francisco Public Library
Biographical Note
1898 Born, New York (?)
1920s-1930s Worked as migrant farm laborer and gold miner in California, Oregon, and Washington
1942 Began work as a longshoreman in San Francisco, California
1951 Author, The True Believer
1955 Author, The Passionate State of Mind
1963 Author, The Ordeal of Change
1967 Author, The Temper of Our Time Invited to the White House by President Lyndon B. Johnson
1967-1969 Wrote nationally syndicated newspaper column, "Reflections"
1968-1969 Member, National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence
1969 Author, Working and Thinking on the Waterfront
1973 Author, Reflections on the Human Condition
1979 Author, Before the Sabbath
1983 Awarded Presidential Medal of Freedom by Ronald Reagan Died, San Francisco, California Autobiography, Truth Imagined, published posthumously
Scope and Content Note
The Eric Hoffer papers represent the largest single fund of primary sources documenting the unusual life and influential writings of a celebrated and controversial individual who came to be known as America's "longshoreman philosopher." The collection contains nearly everything ever written by Hoffer, including copious notes made throughout his lifetime, as well as a large volume of correspondence from readers of his works. There are also newspaper columns and audiovisual materials which, taken together with his writings, reveal a fuller picture of Hoffer as not only the solitary thinker, but a public figure engaged with the world around him.
The documents in the Hoffer collection concern all periods of his life, and they include early, unpublished stories based on his experiences as a migrant worker and sometime gold miner in California during the Depression. Although living at the very margins of society, Hoffer made great efforts to educate himself on a wide variety of subjects. The NOTEBOOKS series provides an annotated record of Hoffer's readings, along with his own observations on many topics. In these notebooks, the genesis of his personal philosophy can be traced, as can the polishing of the aphoristic style that characterized much of his published work. Hoffer continued his practice of keeping notebooks until late in his life, and these contain much unpublished material, a large portion of which was transcribed before his death and is part of the collection.
Hoffer's first published work, The True Believer (1951), brought him enduring acclaim for its analysis of mass movements in history and Hoffer's emphasis on the part played by fanaticism in the trajectory of such movements. The term "true believer" entered the popular vocabulary as an archetype of the political or religious zealot, and Hoffer's book is still invoked in contemporary discussions of religious fundamentalism and political terrorism. The collection contains early drafts of this seminal work, as well as its final manuscript form.
Hoffer, who worked for many years as a longshoreman on the San Francisco docks, went on to write other books ( The Ordeal of Change and The Temper of Our Time, among others) in which he set forth his ideas on history and social change, the relationship of humanity to nature, and what, in Hoffer's view, was the often suspect role played by intellectuals as exponents of absolutist doctrine and as seekers of power for themselves. Following several programs devoted to him on national television in the 1960s, Hoffer became a public personality, and through numerous speeches and a syndicated newspaper column, he participated vocally in the often strident debates over foreign and domestic policy in the United States during the Vietnam War era.
The SPEECHES AND WRITINGS series of the Hoffer collection contains the manuscript drafts of most of his books, as well as copies of the numerous articles he wrote for various publications. Among the manuscripts, there are the original diaries used as the basis for Working and Thinking on the Waterfront, and some later diary entries. An unpublished work, "Quotations and Comments," which Hoffer was working on at the time of his death, can also be found in this series. Hoffer's notecards, where he compiled a vast number of citations from various authors and which formed the raw material for much of his writing, comprise the CARD FILE series of the collection.
The collection contains the entire run of Hoffer's syndicated newspaper column, "Reflections," where for several years he wrote on many topical subjects, such as student protest and black militancy, in an often vigorously polemical style. There are also videotape recordings of television interviews made with Hoffer in the 1960s, as well as video and sound recordings of some his public appearances.
The extensive CORRESPONDENCE series of the collection reflects the large audience for Hoffer's work, and also details his relationships with publishers and editors, including the early encouragement of his writing by Margaret Anderson and Elizabeth Lawrence. There is a separate series for the correspondence of Eric Hoffer's longtime companion, Lili Fabilli Osborne.
There are also substantial materials concerning Hoffer's sometimes stormy tenure as a member of the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence, as well as ones relating to his time on the San Francisco Art Commission. The collection also includes a significant amount of biographical and critical writings on Hoffer.
Additional primary documents relating to Eric Hoffer can be found in the collections of the San Francisco Public Library and the Immigration History Research Center of the University of Minnesota (Margaret Anderson collection and the papers of the organization and publication with which Anderson was affiliated, the Common Council for American Unity and Common Ground).
Political psychology.; Violence--United States.; Intellectuals--United States.; United States--Social conditions--1945-; Social psychology.; Philosophy.; Video tapes.
- Biographical File, 1952-1985
  Scope and Contents note
  Addresses, articles and clippings, bibliography, biographies, certificates, diplomas, itineraries, membership books, memorial register and resolutions, obituaries, programs, scrapbook, studies, arranged alphabetically by physical form, and subject file, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Addresses (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Articles and clippings about or mentioning Eric Hoffer
    - 1952-1960 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - 1961-1966 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 1: 4-5)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - 1975-1978 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - 1979-1983 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Bibliography (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Biographies
    - Typescript papers by Stanford Erickson, Sheila K. Johnson, and two anonymous authors, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - "Profiles: The Creative Situation" by Calvin Tomkins, The New Yorker, 1967 January 7 (Box-folder 2: 8)
      Printed copies
    - Eric Hoffer: An American Odyssey by Calvin Tomkins, 1968 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
      Proofs and correspondence
    - "Eric Hoffer: The Crowded Life," documentary produced by WPBT, Miami, Florida, 1968 (Box-folder 3: 3)
      Press release and publicity materials
    - America's Sunset Coast by Merrill Windsor, monograph containing a written profile and photographic illustration of Hoffer, 1978 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      Printed copy
  - Certificate for prayers offered on behalf of Hoffer, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Certificates of appreciation from the National Advisory Council of the Peace Corps and the Western Pension Conference, 1974, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Diplomas for honorary degrees awarded to Hoffer, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 4: 1-3)
  - Itineraries, undated (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Membership books, International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, 1948-1959 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Memorial register, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Memorial resolutions passed by the San Francisco Board of Supervisors and Santa Monica City Council, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    Includes correspondence.
  - Obituaries, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
  - Programs for events honoring or involving Eric Hoffer, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Scrapbook compiled by Margaret Anderson, consisting largely of reviews and articles relating to Eric Hoffer, circa 1952 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Studies by others on Eric Hoffer, 1955-1973
    - Doctoral dissertations, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 5: 2-3)
    - Doctoral dissertation, 1974 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Papers, 1955-1973 (Box-folder 6: 2-6)
  - Subject file, 1955-1985
    - Awards, 1955-1983 (Box-folder 7: 1)
      Correspondence and programs relating to Hoffer's receipt of the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the Commonwealth Club of California Literature Award, the Myrtle Wreath Award, and a grant from the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    - Lili Fabilli and Eric Hoffer Essay Prize, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 7: 2)
      Brochures, correspondence, essay, and poster relating to a prize established at the University of California at Berkeley.
    - Memorial sculpture, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 7: 3-5)
      Clippings, correspondence, programs, guest list, press release, reports, and speeches relating to the commissioning and dedication in San Francisco of the "Skygate" sculpture in honor of Eric Hoffer.
- Correspondence, 1941-1983
  Letters and cards, with some enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General
    - Birthday cards (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
    - Christmas cards (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Christmas cards (Box-folder 8: 1-5)
    - Christmas cards (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - Speaking invitations
      - 1951-1962 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 10: 1-4)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 11: 3-5)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 12: 3-4)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 12: 5)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 13: 2)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 13: 3)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 13: 4)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 13: 7)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 13: 8)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 13: 9)
      - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - A (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
    - B (Box-folder 14: 3-5)
    - B (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - C (Box-folder 15: 2-5)
    - D (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
    - E (Box-folder 16: 2-4)
    - F (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - F (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - G (Box-folder 17: 2-4)
    - H (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - H (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - I (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - J (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - K (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - K (Box-folder 19: 1-2)
    - L (Box-folder 19: 3-5)
    - M (Box-folder 20: 1-4)
    - N (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - O (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - P (Box-folder 21: 3-5)
    - Q (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - R (Box-folder 22: 2-4)
    - S (Box-folder 22: 5-6)
    - S (Box-folder 23: 1-4)
    - T (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - T (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - U (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - V (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - W (Box-folder 24: 4-5)
    - W (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Y (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Z (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Alinsky, Saul D., 1958-1962 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Alioto, Joseph L., 1968-1972 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Altschuler, Irene Kaeppler, 1968 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1955 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - The American Spectator (Erich Eichman, Baron Von Kannon), 1980 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Anderson, M. Margaret, 1941-1976 (Box-folder 25: 10)
  - Anthony, Aristotle, 1966 (Box-folder 25: 11)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1955 (Box-folder 25: 12)
  - The Asia Foundation (Harry H. Pierson, Robert V. Sedwick), 1955-1959 (Box-folder 25: 13)
  - Austin, Ken, 1952 (Box-folder 25: 14)
  - Author's Guild, Inc. (Rex Stout), 1972 (Box-folder 25: 15)
  - Baker, Bruce, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - Baker, James, 1979 (Box-folder 25: 17)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1975 (Box-folder 25: 18)
  - Bay, Christian, 1959 (Box-folder 25: 19)
  - Bendix, Reinhard, 1955 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Berger, Lawrence, 1964 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Bergson, Bryan, 1960 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Bernstein, Dave, undated (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Bethell, Tom, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Black, Ron, 1980 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Boime, Jerome, 1964 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Bond, T. Bruce, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Boston University Libraries (Howard B. Gotlieb, G. A. Harrer), 1965-1978 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1962 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Bowling, John W., 1964-1976 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Bradner, Hugh, 1967 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Broad, Charles W., 1964 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Brodie, Howard, 1965 (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - Brown, Barney, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - Brown, F. Reese, 1952 (Box-folder 26: 16)
  - Bull, Nina, 1956 (Box-folder 26: 17)
  - Bunzel, John, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 26: 18)
  - Burdick, Eugene, 1964 (Box-folder 26: 19)
  - Burger, Warren E., 1969-1981 (Box-folder 26: 20)
  - Burns, James MacGregor, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 21)
  - Bush, George, 1983 (Box-folder 26: 22)
  - Campbell, James H., 1967 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (John David Hamilton, Fred Harris, John McGreevy, Susan Murgatroyd, Thelma Rosen), 1967-1974 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Carruthers, John D., 1968-1971 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Caudill, Philip R., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Cavalier (Robert J. Shea), 1966 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Cereghino, Ed, 1964-1974 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Chagi, Karen, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Chester, Kathryn, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Childs, Richard F., 1966 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Citizen Exchange Corps (Stephen D. James), 1967 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Citizens Committee for Peace with Freedom in Vietnam (Omar N. Bradley, Paul H. Douglas), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Colby, Kenneth Mark, 1952 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Coldren, Lee, 1963 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Cole, Newton, undated (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - Cole, Stacy, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), Inc. (Jack Beck, Albert Feldman, John Flynn, Donald C. Hamilton, Anthony Janak, David Klinger, Enid Moore), 1956-1969 (Box-folder 27: 16)
    General note
    See also: Sevareid, Eric
  - Comfort, Frances, 1952 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - Connell, William, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 27: 18)
  - Connelly, Dave, 1963 (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Covert, Jim, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 27: 20)
  - Coward-McCann, Inc., 1964-1970 (Box-folder 27: 21)
  - Cox, Martha Heasley, 1965 (Box-folder 27: 22)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (Allan C. Collins, Perry H. Knowlton, Joan Mann, Maureen Walters, Mollie Waters), 1958-1982 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Dagani, Nahum and Sarah, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Dale, William, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - D'Amboise, Jacques, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Danhurst, Donald, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Davidson, Ian, 1968 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Dayan, Stanley, 1969 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - DePauw University (William E. Kerstetter, Norman J. Knights, Dwight L. Ling), 1971-1972 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Di Cyan, Erwin, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Donovan, Richard, 1951 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Doubleday and Co. (Judith Dollenmayer, Diane Matthews), 1967-1976 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Doyle, Dennis P., 1964-1979 (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - Dreher, Fred, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Dudley, Marilyn Rice, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Duke University (Mary Featherstone, Edgar T. Thompson), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 28: 15)
  - Dunne, Gerald T., 1972 (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Dyer, Frederick C., 1975-1982 (Box-folder 28: 17)
  - Dyke, William D., 1970 (Box-folder 28: 18)
  - E. P. Dutton and Co. (John Macrae III), 1968-1976 (Box-folder 28: 19)
  - Edises, Ed, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 28: 20)
  - Egan, William T., 1969 (Box-folder 28: 21)
  - Emhecht, Miklos P., 1965-1973 (Box-folder 28: 22)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Lucette Miller, Bonnie Oberman, Joseph H. Soulak), 1962-1981 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Erickson, Stanford, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Esquire (Byron Dobell, Don Erickson, Harold Hayes, W. H. Honan), 1963-1969 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Fabilli, Albert, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Fabilli, Giacinta, undated (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Fabilli, Josephine, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Fabilli, Lili [See: Osborne, Lili Fabilli]
  - Fabilli, Mary, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Fabilli, Virginia, 1973 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Farricielli, Susan, 1968 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Felix, Jean, undated (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - Ferguson, Charles W., 1965-1967 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Finefrock, John H., 1973-1976 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Fischer, John, 1967 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Fitzgerald, Ed, 1980 (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Flack, Michael J., 1970 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Flesch, Rudolf, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 29: 16)
  - Folger, Ruth Loring, 1962 (Box-folder 29 :17)
  - Forbes, Jill, 1975 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Foundation for Research and Education on Eugenics and Dysgenics (Robert E. Kuttner), 1971 (Box-folder 29: 19)
  - Frame, Donald M., 1970-1973 (Box-folder 29: 20)
  - Frank, Jerome N., 1951 (Box-folder 29: 21)
  - Frary, Chris, undated (Box-folder 29: 22)
  - Fredlund, William, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 29: 23)
  - Freedoms Foundation, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 29: 24)
  - The Fund for the Republic, Inc., 1958 (Box-folder 29: 25)
  - Geyer, Georgie Anne, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Gordon, Mitchell, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Governors State University (William H. Dodd, Cliff Eagleton, Kiyo Mori, Virginia L. Piucci), 1977 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - Green, Edith, 1969 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Groot, Monique de, 1960 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Hagen, Beulah, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Hamill, Paul, undated (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Hardy, Sophie, 1952 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Harlan, Douglas, 1968 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Harley, Alexander and Frances, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - Harper and Row (Simon Michael Bessie, Cass Canfield, Rose Daly, John Fischer, Anne Flagg, Lucy Guerlac, Beulah Hagen, Elizabeth Lawrence, John Leggett, Corona Machemer, John Macrae, Pat McNees, Antonia Racchiele, Jane Shapiro)
    - 1952-1960 (Box-folder 30: 11)
    - 1961-1964 (Box-folder 30: 12)
    - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 30: 13)
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 30: 14)
    - 1969-1970 (Box-folder 30: 15)
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 30: 16)
    - 1973-1975 (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - 1976-1979 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - 1980-1983 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Harper's (Frederick L. Allen, Jeffrey Burke, John Fischer, Alice F. Fix, Herman Gollob, Lewis Lapham, Catherine Meyer), 1952-1977 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Harris, Alice G., 1964 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Harrison, Theodore, 1968 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Hayakawa, S. I., 1964-1975 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Hazlehurst, Sam, 1965 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Hazzard, Mrs., undated (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Herbert, John W., Jr., 1978 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Hickel, Walter J., 1971-1979 (Box-folder 31: 11)
  - Hill, Jim, 1967 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - Hillman, Richard, 1969 (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Hinckley, Jean, 1978 (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Hinderaker, Birk and Ivan, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Hirsch, Gideon, 1967 (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Hodgdon, Keith, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Hogg, Thomas C., 1968 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Holberg, Mary, 1965 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Holdren, Dick, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - Holiday (Martha J. Casselman, Ruth Graves), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Holman, William R., 1968 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Holzer, Purl E., 1951 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Horwitt, Sanford D., 1980 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Hough, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 32: 9)
  - Howes, Dorothy J., 1952 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Hruska, Roman L., 1968 (Box-folder 32: 11)
  - Hudson Institute (Gail D. Kings, Gail L. Potter), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1968-1971 (Box-folder 32: 13)
  - Hurst, W. Calvin, 1976 (Box-folder 32: 14)
  - IBM (Harry J. Orchard), 1968 (Box-folder 32: 15)
  - Ichord, Richard, 1969 (Box-folder 32: 16)
  - Ingram, Louise, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 32: 17)
  - Institute for Educational Affairs (Phillip Marcus), 1982 (Box-folder 32: 18)
  - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (Bill Bailey, William Glazier, John R. Hahn, James R. Herman, Jim Kearney, D. Lindberg), 1960-1980 (Box-folder 32: 19)
  - Jacobson, Ellie, 1966 (Box-folder 32: 20)
  - Jacobson, Jeanne, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 32: 21)
  - Jacobson, Kenny, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 32: 22)
  - Jacobson, Norman, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 32: 23)
  - Janos, Leo H., 1968 (Box-folder 32: 24)
  - Jelliffe, Belinda, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 32: 25)
  - Jensen, Lars Herluf, 1967 (Box-folder 32: 26)
  - Johnson, Ken, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 32: 27)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. and Lady Byrd, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 32: 28)
  - Jones, George Lewis, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 32: 29)
  - Kahn, Herman, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Kalif, George, undated (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Kennedy, Katherine, 1959 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - KGO Radio (John Hewitt, Agar Jaicks), 1973 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Kimble, Lester L., 1968 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Kittrell, Charlie M., 1976-1983 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Klussmann, Frieda, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Knight, George and Dora, 1964-1983 (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - Koerner, James D., 1969-1982 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - KPFA Radio (Eleanor Moore), 1951 (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - KPIX Television (Wayne L. Cain, Caryl Coleman, Art Dlugach, Marvin Hall, Sylvia Hernandez, Dave Horwitz, Fred Joslyn), 1964-1973 (Box-folder 33: 11)
  - KQED Television (Helen Adler, Buzz Anderson, Joyce Campbell, James Day, Arthur Hough, Peggy Little, Richard O. Moore, Winifred Murphy, Stephanie Pincson), 1962-1979 (Box-folder 33: 12)
  - Kristol, Irving, 1970 (Box-folder 33: 13)
  - Krugman, Herbert, 1951 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Kuettner, Al, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - Laird, Melvin, 1970 (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - Lane Community College (Bert Dotson, Terry Ann Forster, I. S. Hakanson, Keith Harker, Dale Parnell, Robert L. Pickering), 1967-1975 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Lawrence, Elizabeth, 1950-1976 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - The Ledger Syndicate, Inc. (John W. Higgins)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 34: 4)